When we speak we create sinusoidal vibrations in the air.
我们讲话时会在空气里生成正弦振动
Higher pitches vibrate faster with a higher frequency than lower pitches.
高音高振动比低音高快 频率也更高
These vibrations can be detected by a microphone and
麦克风会检测出这类振动
transduced from acoustical energy carried in the sound wave,
然后将声波携带的声能量转换成
to electrical energy where it is recorded as an audio signal.
电能 以音频信号的形式记录下来
The audio signal for hello world looks like this.
词组 hello world (你好世界) 的音频信号看起来像这样
As in any other kind of modeling,
就像处理其它模型
we need to get a handle on the features that make up our input.
我们需要处理组成输入的特征
So, what's going on in this signal?
那这个信号的特征是什么呢？
We can see that it seems to be in two blobs and
我们可以发现 这个信号看起来像是在两个斑点里
those blobs do correspond to the two words, hello and world.
这些斑点又恰与 hello 和 world 这两个单词对应
We also see immediately that some of the vibrations in
我们还可以发现 信号的有些振动
the signal are taller than the others or have a higher amplitude.
要比其它振动高 也就是振幅较大
The amplitude in the audio signal tells us how much acoustical energy is in the sound,
音频信号的振幅体现了声音所含声能量的多少
how loud it is.
也就是声音有多大声
If we look closer at a time slice of the signal,
取一小块时间切片 我们来进一步观察这个信号
we can see it has an irregular wiggle shape to it.
我们会发现信号具不规则波动的形状
Our speech is made up of many frequencies at the same time.
语音是由许多频率同时组成的
The signal we see here is really a sum of all those frequencies stuck together.
我们这里看到的信号实际上是所有频率加在一起的总和
To properly analyze the signal,
要恰当地分析信号
we would like to use the component frequencies as features.
我们需要把频率成分当特征来处理
We can use a fourier transform to break the signal into these components.
我们可以用傅里叶变换把信号分解为这些频率成分
The FFT algorithm or Fast Fourier Transform,
FFT 算法 也就是快速傅里叶变换
is widely available for this task.
十分适用于这个任务
We can use this splitting technique to convert the sound to a Spectrogram.
我们可以用这个分离技术把声音转为频谱图
In this Spectrogram of the hello world phrase,
短语 hello world 的频谱图
we see the frequency on the vertical axis plotted against the time,
竖轴表示频率
on the horizontal axis.
横轴则表示时间
The intensity of shading indicates the amplitude of the signal.
阴影强度表示信号的振幅
To create a Spectrogram first,
要创建频谱图 首先
divide the signal into time frames.
按时帧分割信号
Then split each frame signal into frequency components with an FFT.
然后 用 FFT 把每帧信号拆分成不同的频率成分
Each time frame is now represented with a vector of amplitudes at each frequency.
这样一来 可用各频率所在的振幅向量来表示各时帧
If we line up the vectors again in their time series order,
把向量按时间序列的顺序重新排好
we can have a visual picture of the sound components, the Spectrogram.
我们就能得到声音成分的可视化图像 也就是频谱图
The Spectrogram can be lined up with the original audio signal in time.
频谱图可以按时间与原始的音频信号并排放置
With the Spectrogram we have a complete representation of our sound data.
通过频谱图 我们就可以完整地把声音数据表示出来
But we still have noise and variability embedded into the data.
但数据里还带有噪声和差异性
In addition, there may be more information here than we really need.
而且 我们可能不需要这么多信息
Next, we'll look at Feature Extraction techniques to, both,
接下来 我们要讲特征提取技术
reduce the noise and reduce the dimensionality of our data.
该技术既可以减少噪声 又能减少数据的维数